Guide to the Montana Power Company Predecessor Company records 1880-1947
Montana Historical Society
- Helena Power Transmission Company
  - Financial Records
    - Miscellaneous (includes invoice for turbine; summary of prices from Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company), 1905-1906 (Box-folder 93 / 6)
  - Legal Documents
    - Grant by United States Secretary of War of right to build dam at Canyon Ferry, 1905 (Box-folder 93 / 7)
    - Power contracts (includes Butte Electric and Power Company, Butte and Superior Copper Company, Missouri River Power Company, Robert Emmett Copper Company, and Washoe Copper Company), 1905-1908 (Box-folder 93 / 8)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock certificates (blank), undated (Box-folder 93 / 9)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1905-1906 (Box-folder 93 / 10)
  - Miscellany
    - Typical section of steel dam (blueprint) [Oversize Box], 1906 (Oversizebox 9)
- Helena Steam Power and Lighting Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1886-1889 (Box-folder 94 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1883-1887 (Box-folder 94 / 2)
    - General ledger, 1887-1889 (Volume 206)
    - Invoices: Brush Electric Company, 1886-1888 (Box-folder 94 / 3)
    - Invoices: Fraser and Chalmers, 1887-1888 (Box-folder 94 / 4)
    - Invoices: A-W, 1888 (Box-folder 94 / 5)
    - Journal, 1884-1887 (Box-folder 94 / 6)
    - Journal, 1888-1889 (Volume 207)
    - Journal, undated (Box-folder 95 / 1)
    - Trial balances, 1888 (Box-folder 95 / 2)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock certificates, undated (Box-folder 95 / 3)
    - Stockholder journal, 1886-1888 (Box-folder 95 / 4)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1886-1888 (Box-folder 95 / 5)
- Helena Street Railway Company
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1886-1890 (Box-folder 95 / 6)
  - Financial Records
    - Checkstubs, 1890 (Box-folder 95 / 7)
    - General ledger, 1886-1890 (Volume 208)
    - Journal, 1886-1890 (Volume 209)
    - Tickets and cash sales, 1886-1890 (Box-folder 95 / 8)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes, etc.), 1886-1891 (Volume 210)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1886-1891 (Box-folder 95 / 9)
    - Stockholder transfer journal, 1886-1891 (Box-folder 95 / 10)
- Helena Water and Electric Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 96 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - General ledgers, 1896-1899 (Volume 211- 212)
    - General ledger, 1899-1902 (Box-folder 96 / 2)
    - Journal, 1896-1902 (Volume 213)
    - Trial balance book (labelled "journal"), 1899-1902 (Box-folder 96 / 3)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stockholder ledger, 1896-1903 (Box-folder 96 / 4)
    - Stockholder transfer book, 1896-1903 (Box-folder 96 / 5)
- Idaho Transmission Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 97 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash books, 1917-1934 (Volume 214- 216)
    - Financial and operating reports, 1929-1936 (Volume 217- 220)
    - General ledgers, 1917-1925 (Box-folder 97 / 2-6)
    - General ledgers, 1926-1930 (Box-folder 98 / 1-6)
    - General ledgers, 1931-1935 (Box-folder 99 / 1-5)
    - General ledger [water damaged, many pages illegible], 1936 (Box-folder 100 / 1)
    - Invoice and journal register, 1918-1928 (Volume 221)
    - Job orders, 1924-1929 (Box-folder 100 / 2)
    - Quarterly physical and service data [Oversize Box], 1930-1936 (Oversizebox 9)
    - Trial balances [Oversize Box], 1918-1926 (Oversizebox 9)
  - Organizational Records
    - Bylaws, 1917 (Box-folder 100 / 3)
    - Stockholder ledger, 1917-1918 (Box-folder 100 / 4)
- Intermountain Power Company
  - Financial Records
    - Estimate of expenses, earnings and capital expenditures under power contracts, 1917-1924 (Box-folder 100 / 5)
  - Legal Documents
    - Power contracts with other power companies and railroads, 1916-1921 (Box-folder 100 / 6)
  - Organizational Records
    - Articles of incorporation; bylaws, 1916-1922 (Box-folder 100 / 7)
- Keating Gold Mining Company
  - Subject File
    - Right of way application for transmission line (includes copies of articles of incorporation, bylaws, etc.), 1908-1913 (Box-folder 100 / 8)
- Lewistown Coal, Gas and Light Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 101 / 1)
  - Court Papers
    - First National Bank of Lewistown vs. Lewistown Coal, Gas and Light Company, 1913 (Box-folder 101 / 2)
    - B.F. Fullmer vs. J.G. Graham and Lewistown Coal, Gas and Light Company, 1910 (Box-folder 101 / 3)
  - Financial Records
    - Accounts due, 1911 (Box-folder 101 / 4)
    - Coal sales ledger: A-Z, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 101 / 5-8)
    - Customer ledger: A-Z, 1910 (Box-folder 102 / 1)
    - General ledger, 1907, 1909 (Box-folder 102 / 2-3)
    - General ledgers, 1908, 1909-1911 (Volume 222- 224)
    - Inventories, 1911 (Box-folder 102 / 4)
    - Trial balance, summary of operations, etc., 1911 (Box-folder 102 / 5)
    - Voucher register, 1909-1911 (Volume 225)
    - Voucher register index, undated (Box-folder 102 / 6)
  - Legal Documents
    - Mortgage; agreements, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 102 / 7)
  - Organizational Records
    - Minutes, 1909, 1911 (Box-folder 102 / 8)
- Lewistown Electric and Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 103 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash books [labelled "Journal"], 1911-1913 (Box-folder 103 / 2-4)
    - Financial statement for merger into Montana Power Company, February 1914 (Box-folder 103 / 5)
    - General ledgers, 1911-1914 (Box-folder 104 / 1-2)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreement: Bank-Electric Building Company, 1912 (Box-folder 104 / 3)
    - Mortgage; voting trust agreement with National Realty Company, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 104 / 4)
  - Organizational Records
    - Stock certificates, 1912-1915 (Box-folder 104 / 5)
- Livingston Coke and Coal Company
  - Miscellany
    - Carbonizing record, 1892-1899 (Volume 226)
- Livingston Water Power Company
  - Historical material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 105 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - General ledger, 1907-1909 (Volume 227)
    - General ledger ["parts of old ledger from 1909 to 19__"], 1909-1919 (Box-folder 105 / 2-3)
    - Trial balance book [labelled "Journal"], 1907-1909 (Box-folder 105 / 4)
    - Voucher registers, 1907-1912 (Volume 228- 229)
  - Organizational Records
    - Minute book, 1891-1908 (Box-folder 105 / 5)
- Madison River Power Company
  - Historical Material
    - Historical information file, undated (Box-folder 106 / 1)
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (re wooden pipes for power site; Bozeman Street Railway Company franchise), 1904-1907 (Box-folder 106 / 2)
  - Financial Records
    - Cash books, 1910-1912 (Volume 230- 231)
    - Customer ledgers, 1905-1913 (Box-folder 106 / 3-6)
    - General ledger, 1905-1906 (Box-folder 107 / 1)
    - General ledger, 1907-1908 (Volume 232)
    - General ledgers, 1909-1912 (Box-folder 107 / 2-3)
    - General ledger: Bozeman branch, 1909-1912 (Box-folder 108 / 1)
    - General ledgers: subsidiaries, 1909-1914 (Box-folder 108 / 2-4)
    - General ledgers: subsidiaries, plant, 1909-1912 (Box-folder 109 / 1)
    - Journal, 1905-1908 (Box-folder 109 / 2)
    - Journal entries from books of Butte Electric and Power Company (re mortgage), 1908 (Box-folder 109 / 3)
    - Voucher registers, 1905-1912 (Volume 233- 236)
    - Miscellaneous (includes record of power sales; investment securities; chart of net income of Company and predecessors), 1893-1912 (Box-folder 109 / 4)
  - Legal Documents
    - Applications for power, 1907-1910 (Box-folder 109 / 5)
    - Deed: The Power Company to Madison River Power Company, 1905 (Box-folder 109 / 6)
    - Lighting contracts: cities of Bozeman and Livingston, 1907-1912 (Box-folder 109 / 7)
    - Mortgages, 1905, 1908 (Box-folder 109 / 8)
    - Power contracts: A-W, 1907-1912 (Box-folder 109 / 9-10)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes articles of incorporation, bylaws, minutes, etc.), 1905-1912 (Volume 237)
    - Stock certificates, 1905-1910 (Box-folder 110 / 1)
    - Stock ownership lists (includes The Power Company; Gallatin Light, Power and Railway Company; Livingston Water Power Company), 1892-1908 (Box-folder 110 / 2)
  - Miscellany
    - Station log: station #2 [diary of operations], 1906-1913 (Box-folder 110 / 3)
- Malta Light and Power Company
  - Reports
    - Report to Public Service Commission by J.H. Bonner, 1919 (Box-folder 110 / 4)
- Mesa Power Company
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Great Falls Townsite Company (re proposal), 1934 (Box-folder 110 / 5)
  - Financial Records
    - Financial and operating reports, 1929-1934 (Volume 238)
    - General ledger, 1914-1934 (Box-folder 110 / 6)
    - Journal, 1914-1934 (Box-folder 110 / 7)
    - Trial balance sheet, December 1930 (Box-folder 110 / 8)
  - Organizational Records
    - Record book (includes bylaws; minutes) [missing p. 1 and last pages], 1914-1933 (Box-folder 110 / 9)
    - Miscellaneous (includes proxies; statement of dissolution), 1933-1936 (Box-folder 110 / 10)
- Missoula Electric Light Company
  - Court Papers
    - Cases re Sioux Half-Breed Script claims, 1893-1894 (Box-folder 111 / 1)
  - Financial Records
    - Inventory, 1892 (Box-folder 111 / 2)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contract with City of Missoula, 1890 (Box-folder 111 / 3)
- Missoula Gas Company
  - Reports
    - Report to Public Service Commission, 1922 (Box-folder 111 / 4)
- Missoula General Electric Company
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - J.T. Fanning, Consulting Engineer, 1895 (Box-folder 111 / 5)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress book, 1893-1896 (Box-folder 111 / 6)
  - Financial Records
    - Consumers register, 1896-1897 (Volume 239)
  - Legal Documents
    - Agreements between Missoula General Electric Company, Brush Electric Company, and Missoula Mercantile Company, 1893-1896 (Box-folder 111 / 7)
    - Motor agreements with General Electric Company, 1915-1924 (Box-folder 111 / 8)
- Missoula Light and Power Company / Missoula Light and Water Company
  - Incoming Correspondence
    - Miscellaneous (includes C.M. McLeod; American Stoker Company), 1904-1922 (Box-folder 112 / 1)
  - Outgoing Correspondence
    - Letterpress copy, May 1892 (Box-folder 112 / 2)
    - Letterpress books (M.R. Rutherford), 1896-1903 (Box-folder 112 / 3-5)
    - Letterpress books (S.R. Inch), 1903 (Box-folder 112 / 6)
    - Letterpress books: Light Dept. (S.R. Inch), 1903-1906 (Box-folder 113 / 1-3)
  - Court Papers
    - Coen-Fisher Company vs. Missoula Light and Water Company, 1914 (Box-folder 114 / 1)
    - James Colligan vs. Missoula Light and Water Company, 1914 (Box-folder 114 / 2)
    - Ellen Dent vs. Missoula Light and Water Company, 1914 (Box-folder 114 / 3)
    - Angelo DeSandro vs. Missoula Light and Water Company, 1911-1915 (Box-folder 114 / 4)
    - Florence Laundry Company vs. Missoula Light and Water Company, 1924 (Box-folder 114 / 5)
    - Missoula Light and Water Company vs. City of Missoula, 1915-1919 (Box-folder 114 / 6)
    - Missoula Light and Water Company vs. Ravalli County, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 114 / 7)
    - Ravalli Land and Irrigation Company vs. Robert S. Nicol et al. (defendants include Missoula Light and Water Company), 1913-1916 (Box-folder 114 / 8)
    - Laura Trainer vs. Missoula Light and Water Company, 1915 (Box-folder 114 / 9)
    - L.E. Tucker vs. Missoula Light and Water Company (transcript on appeal), 1926 (Box-folder 114 / 10)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 114 / 11)
  - Employment Records
    - Employee accidents (includes deaths of A.C. Clark and E.A. Cummings), 1904-1917 (Box-folder 114 / 12-14)
    - Employee statements of understanding of dangers of job, 1913 (Box-folder 114 / 15)
    - Payroll: Hamilton departments, 1910-1916 (Box-folder 114 / 16)
    - Payroll: Hamilton departments, 1917-1924 (Box-folder 115 / 1-2)
    - Payroll: Light Department, 1902-1911 (Box-folder 115 / 3-13)
    - Payroll: Light Department, 1912-1918 (Box-folder 116 / 1-7)
    - Payroll: Light Department, 1919-1922 (Box-folder 117 / 1-8)
    - Payroll: Light Department, 1923-1925 (Box-folder 118 / 1-6)
    - Payroll: Office, 1907-1924 (Box-folder 119 / 1-3)
    - Payroll: Water Department [earlier payrolls in Missoula Water Company subgroup], 1904-1914 (Box-folder 119 / 4-9)
  - Financial Records
    - Annual financial report to State Board of Equalization, 1919-1924 (Box-folder 120 / 1)
    - Cancelled checks [sampled], 1906-1910 (Box-folder 120 / 2)
    - Cash books, 1896-1925 (Volume 240- 246)
    - Cash books: Hamilton / Bitter Root Valley System (includes Hamilton Light and Water Company), 1910-1925 (Volume 247- 250)
    - Consumer registers: Light Dept. [note: there are 2 volumes 1907-1908 one labelled "register" one labelled "ledger". One is possibly mislabelled and may be 1908-1909], 1898-1908 (Volume 251- 259)
    - Corporate income tax, 1910, 1918 (Box-folder 120 / 3)
    - Daily Heating Dept. Station reports, 1909-1912 (Volume 260- 263)
    - Daily Light Dept. Substation reports, 1911-1912 (Volume 264- 265)
    - Dividing wall expenditures, 1921-1924 (Box-folder 120 / 4)
    - Financial statements (includes both Missoula and Bitter Root Valley), 1900-1908 (Box-folder 120 / 5-8)
    - Financial statements (includes Missoula only) [Oversize Box], 1908-1910 (Oversizebox 9)
    - Financial statements (includes both Missoula and Bitter Root Valley), 1911-1913 (Box-folder 120 / 9-11)
    - Financial statements (includes both Missoula and Bitter Root Valley), 1914-1918 (Box-folder 121 / 1-5)
    - Financial statements (includes both Missoula and Bitter Root Valley), 1919-1923 (Box-folder 122 / 1-5)
    - Financial statements (includes both Missoula and Bitter Root Valley) [continued in Missoula Public Service Company subgroup], 1924 (Box-folder 123 / 1)
    - Financial statements: Bitter Root Valley System (includes information not contained in joint statement), 1912-1914, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 123 / 2-6)
    - Financial statements: Bitter Root Valley System (includes information not contained in joint statement) [continued in Missoula Public Service Company subgroup], 1921-1924 (Box-folder 124 / 1-4)
    - Financial statements: Heating Dept., 1906-1907 (Box-folder 124 / 5)
    - General ledger, 1912-1913 (Box-folder 124 / 6)
    - General ledgers, 1896-1926 (Volume 266- 273)
    - General ledger indexes [Oversize Box], 1920-1926 (Oversizebox 9)
    - General ledger: Hamilton, 1910 (Box-folder 125 / 1)
    - General ledgers: Hamilton / Bitter Root Valley System (includes Hamilton Light and Water Company), 1910-1923 (Volume 274- 278)
    - Heating plant fuel reports, 1910-1912 (Box-folder 125 / 2)
    - Insurance: automobile, 1920-1925 (Box-folder 125 / 3-5)
    - Insurance: fire, 1918-1924 (Box-folder 125 / 6-8)
    - Insurance: surety, 1906-1924 (Box-folder 125 / 9)
    - Insurance: miscellaneous, 1908-1912 (Box-folder 125 / 10)
    - Insurance policy lists, 1922-1928 (Box-folder 125 / 11)
    - Inventories, 1902-1907 (Box-folder 125 / 12-13)
    - Inventories, 1913-1923 (Box-folder 126 / 1-4)
    - Inventories: Bitter Root Valley System, 1915-1923 (Box-folder 126 / 5-7)
    - Inventory: ranch, 1914 (Box-folder 126 / 8)
    - Invoices and bills [removed from ledger], 1912-1913 (Box-folder 126 / 9)
    - Journal, 1902-1903 (Box-folder 126 / 10)
    - Journal / trial balances, 1904-1928 (Volume 279- 282)
    - Journal / trial balances: Hamilton / Bitter Root Valley System (includes Hamilton Water and Power Company), 1910-1925 (Volume 283- 286)
    - Ledger (re building of Gates Dam), 1905-1908 (Box-folder 127 / 1)
    - List of account numbers: Light Dept., 1910 (Box-folder 127 / 2)
    - Proof of solvency submitted to Montana Industrial Accident Board, 1922-1923 (Box-folder 127 / 3)
    - Ranch charges (includes apple orders), circa 1913 (Box-folder 127 / 4)
    - Repair book [Oversize Box], 1896-1899 (Oversizebox 10)
    - Spillway gates expenditures, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 127 / 5)
    - Statement of steam furnished to H.E. Chaney for Florence Laundry and Florence Hotel, 1909 (Box-folder 127 / 6)
    - Taxes, 1909-1911 (Box-folder 127 / 7)
    - Trial balance books, 1896-1904 (Box-folder 127 / 8-9)
    - Voucher registers, 1904-1928 (Volume 287- 298)
    - Voucher registers: Hamilton / Bitter Root Valley System (includes Hamilton Water and Power Company), 1910-1928 (Volume 299- 301)
    - Water customers [Oversize Box], 1910-1920 (Oversizebox 10)
    - Work order book, 1911-1913 (Box-folder 127 / 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1897-1924 (Box-folder 127 / 11)
  - Hearings
    - Public Service Commission Docket #409 "Upon the initial motion of the Commission against the Missoula Light and Water Company in the matter of alleged excessive and unreasonable rates charged for electric service", 1914 (Box-folder 128 / 1)
    - Public Service Commission Docket #477 "Upon the initial motion of the Commission to require all water utilities to show cause why the Commission should not promulgate standard rules and regulations", 1915 (Box-folder 128 / 2)
    - Public Service Commission Docket #856 "Upon the initial motion of the Public Service Commission of Montana vs. Missoula Light and Water Company and Missoula Street Railway Company", 1924 (Box-folder 128 / 3)
  - Legal Documents
    - Contracts: Bitter Root Stock Farm, 1910, 1913 (Box-folder 128 / 4)
    - Contracts: Bitter Root Valley, 1910-1913 (Box-folder 128 / 5)
    - Contracts: Continental Oil Company, 1913-1924 (Box-folder 128 / 6)
    - Contracts: decorative lighting, 1907-1915 (Box-folder 128 / 7)
    - Contracts: George Dietrich and Company (re sidewalks, walls, etc.), 1912 (Box-folder 128 / 8)
    - Contracts: electric lighting service, 1909-1917 (Box-folder 128 / 9-10)
    - Contracts: electric lighting service, Hamilton, 1911-1923 (Box-folder 128 / 11)
    - Contracts: electric power service, 1909-1912 (Box-folder 128 / 12)
    - Contracts: Electro Bleaching Gas Company (re chlorine for water supply), 1920-1923 (Box-folder 128 / 13)
    - Contracts: extension of distribution system, Heating Dept., 1922-1923 (Box-folder 128 / 14)
    - Contracts: Fort Missoula, 1910-1924 (Box-folder 128 / 15)
    - Contracts: General Electric Company, 1901-1924 (Box-folder 129 / 1-2)
    - Contracts: Adam Hadalin (re excavating), 1910-1914 (Box-folder 129 / 3)
    - Contracts: Hot Point Electric Company, 1912-1920 (Box-folder 129 / 4)
    - Contracts: incandescent lights, 1911-1925 (Box-folder 129 / 5-7)
    - Contracts: International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, 1907-1921 (Box-folder 129 / 8)
    - Contracts: line extensions, 1917 (Box-folder 129 / 9)
    - Contracts: Masonic Temple Association of Missoula, 1909-1919 (Box-folder 129 / 10)
    - Contracts: City of Missoula, 1888-1917 (Box-folder 129 / 11)
    - Contracts: Missoula Federal Building, 1920-1924 (Box-folder 129 / 12)
    - Contracts: Missoula Mercantile Company, 1906, 1912 (Box-folder 129 / 13)
    - Contracts: Missoula Real Estate Association, 1906-1912 (Box-folder 130 / 1)
    - Contracts: Nelson and Pederson contractors, 1909-1913, undated (Box-folder 130 / 2)
    - Contracts: Northern Pacific Railway Company, 1896-1924 (Box-folder 130 / 3)
    - Contracts: painters, 1920-1923 (Box-folder 130 / 4)
    - Contracts: Postal Telegraph Cable Company, 1910-1922 (Box-folder 130 / 5)
    - Contracts: Roundup Coal Company, 1912-1920 (Box-folder 130 / 6)
    - Contracts: Stirling Consolidated Boiler Company, 1906 (Box-folder 130 / 7)
    - Contracts: telephones (includes Rocky Mountain Bell Telephone Company; Montana Independent Telephone Company), 1905-1913 (Box-folder 130 / 8)
    - Contracts: Westinghouse Electric and Manufacturing Company, 1911-1922 (Box-folder 130 / 9)
    - Contracts: B-W, 1897-1924 (Box-folder 130 / 10-11)
    - Deeds, 1907-1924 (Box-folder 130 / 12)
    - Franchise ordinances (includes Bozeman, Great Falls, Hamilton, Missoula, Stevensville, 1886-1914 (Box-folder 130 / 13)
    - Leases, 1905-1924 (Box-folder 130 / 14)
    - Liability releases, 1906-1921 (Box-folder 130 / 15)
    - Mortgage: Florence Hotel (includes inventory of contents), 1924 (Box-folder 130 / 16)
    - Mortgages: miscellaneous, 1896-1924 (Box-folder 130 / 17)
    - Pole line extension agreements, 1923, 1926, undated (Box-folder 130 / 18)
    - Rights of way and easements, 1909-1921 (Box-folder 130 / 19)
    - Water main extension agreements, 1915-1922 (Box-folder 130 / 20)
  - Organizational Records
    - Annual statements of corporation, 1906, 1919-1923 (Box-folder 131 / 1)
    - Record book (includes articles of incorporation; minutes), 1903-1918 (Box-folder 131 / 2)
    - Stock certificates, 1896-1903 (Box-folder 131 / 3)
    - Miscellaneous (includes proxies, statement of increase of stock, decree of dissolution), 1903-1925 (Box-folder 131 / 4)
  - Reports
    - Report by E.D. Hathaway on plan to divert Gold Creek water, 1923 (Box-folder 131 / 5)
    - Reports by Public Service Commission engineers J.H. Bonner and W.B. Saunders, 1918, 1922 (Box-folder 131 / 6)
    - Reports by Public Service Commission engineer H.S. Snell, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 131 / 7-8)
    - Reports of water utility to Public Service Commission, 1917 (Box-folder 131 / 9)
  - Subject Files
    - Physical plant, 1903-1910 (Box-folder 131 / 10)
    - Rates and tariffs filed with Public Service Commission, 1913-1922 (Box-folder 131 / 11-12)
    - Steam heating system (includes report and proposal of P.A. Williams), 1909 (Box-folder 132 / 1)
    - Stirling boilers (includes proposal of Charles C. Moore and Company), 1913, 1915 (Box-folder 132 / 2)
    - Water main extensions, 1914-1923 (Box-folder 132 / 3)
  - Miscellany
    - Application register (indexed), 1906-1921 (Box-folder 132 / 4-5)
    - Card announcing recycling of light bulbs, 1910 (Box-folder 132 / 6)
    - Engineers drawings #A2001-A2041, 1910-1923 (Box-folder 132 / 7)
    - Field books (include entries for Clark-Missoula Realty Company and Clark Montana Power Company), 1911-1914, undated (Box-folder 132 / 8)
    - Furnaces, 1914-1915 (Box-folder 132 / 9)
    - List of ownership, Rattlesnake Valley, 1910 (Box-folder 132 / 10)
    - Orders for equipment (includes specifications), 1910-1924 (Box-folder 132 / 11)
    - Tests of Westinghouse steam turbine, 1905 (Box-folder 132 / 12)
    - United States census return: electric light and power stations, 1912 (Box-folder 132 / 13)
    - Work order stub books, 1916-1919 (Box-folder 132 / 14)
- Missoula Public Service Company
  - Court Papers
    - W.L. Brewer vs. Missoula Public Service Company, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 133 / 1-2)
    - H.M. Davis vs. Missoula Public Service Company, 1928-1929 (Box-folder 133 / 3)
    - City of Hamilton vs. Missoula Public Service Company, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 133 / 4)
    - Joseph Johns and Nazema Johns vs. Missoula Public Service Company, 1928 (Box-folder 133 / 5)
    - Missoula Public Service Company vs. Bitter Root Irrigation District, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 133 / 6)
    - L.E. Tucker vs. Missoula Public Service Company, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 133 / 7-8)
    - Hulda Wakefield vs. Missoula Public Service Company, 1925 (Box-folder 133 / 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1928 (Box-folder 133 / 10)
  - Employment Records
    - Payroll [earlier payrolls in Missoula Light and Water Company subgroup], 1925 (Box-folder 133 / 11)
    - Payroll, 1926-1929 (Box-folder 134 / 1-8)
    - Payroll: Hamilton, 1925-1930 (Box-folder 134 / 9-10)
    - Payroll: office, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 135 / 1-2)
  - Financial Records
    - Annual financial reports to State Board of Equalization, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 135 / 3)
    - Cash book, 1925-1930 (Volume 302)
    - Cash book: Bitter Root Valley System, 1925-1929 (Volume 303)
    - Corporation income tax questionnaire, 1928 (Box-folder 135 / 4)